Andre De Coppet Collection, 1566-1936 (bulk 1770-1865 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Miscellaneous, 1703-1869; 3 boxes (1 partial)
  - British Shipping, 1778 October 10-1813 November 29; 1 folder
    - Prize Certificate, 1813 November 29; 1 item (Folder 4)
      Printed form certifying that Benjamin Jefson served on board His Majesty's Ship Shannon from 1808 until his death in 1813 at the age of fifteen. Signed by Captain P. B. V. Broke. On the back is a record of his prize money and his father's signature verifying receipt of the money owed his late son. 2 pp.
  - Broadsides, 1775-1837 September 5; portion of 1 box
    This file consists of miscellaneous broadsides. Researchers should note that additional groups of broadsides can be found under Continental Congress, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island. All are housed in the same box.
    - Broadsides, 1775; 1 item
      Lord Camden's Speech on the New England Fishery Bill. Printed by S. Southwick, Newport. Probable date.
    - Broadsides, 1775 October 26; 1 item
      His Majesty's Most Gracious Speech to Both Houses of Parliament, on Thursday the 26th Day of October, 1775. Outlining his stance toward the rebellious colonies.
    - Broadsides, 1779 March 19; 1 item
      A Proclamation for a General Fast, by order of the Council and House of Representatives of the State of New Hampshire. Printed by Zechariah Fowle, Exeter, New Hampshire.
    - Broadsides, 1783 October 27; 1 item
      Copy of a letter announcing the signing of the Treaty of Paris. Printed by Henry Barber.
    - Broadsides, 1786 September 18; 1 item
      Resolve of Congress prohibiting states from paying the federal government with bills or credit. Signed Charles Thompson, Secretary.
    - Broadsides, 1815 February 14; 1 item
      Announcing a treaty of peace between America and Great Britain [ending the War of 1812].
    - Broadsides, 1837 September 5; 1 item
      Vindiciae Hibernicae. Enlisting subscribers for the purchase of a book vindicating the Irish nation. Issued by publishers R. P. and Thomas Desilver.
  - Census, circa 1790; 1 item (Folder 5)
    Contemporary Ms, listing 16 districts, including the Southwest and Northwest territories. From the Jefferson-Humphreys papers. 1 p. [ Item is missing as of fall 2008.]
  - Commonplace Book (Miscellany), 1700s; 10; 1 item
    Compiler unknown. Containing extracts from various books and publications including: proposals for carrying on an effectual war in America against the French & Spaniards; memoirs of the Lord High Chancellors, Lord Keepers, and Lord Commissioners of the Great Seal of Great Britain; extracts from The History of Hertfordshire; extracts about the history of England. 66 pp., bound.
  - Currency, 1756-1863; 1 folder
    One folder containing early American currency and items related to the same. The De Coppet collection at Princeton also includes several hundred pieces of paper money housed in the Princeton Numismatic Collection, Firestone Library. These are chiefly issues of the American colonies before the Revolution and of the Continental Congress. The collection is in the process of online cataloguing and digitization; those pieces catalogued to date can be found through a search by donor at the Numismatic Collection. For more information contact the Curator of Numismatics.
    - Bills, 1775-1863; 1 item (Folder 6)
      Miscellaneous currency. Included are multiple bills issued by "The United Colonies" in 1775 (printed by Hall and Sellers), a 1779 Massachusetts-Bay bill, a 1780 United States bill, and 1863 Alabama Bills issued under the Confederate States. 11 items.
    - Account Books, 1756; 1 item (Folder 6)
      Two small account books containing tables for converting old tenor into lawful money. One is labeled as belonging to Thomas Gill, Jr.
  - Insurance Policies, 1759-1837; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    Miscellaneous insurance contracts. Included are policies insuring cargo on brigantines Marquis La Fayette and Harriet, a Philadelphia policy for insuring houses from loss by fire, three documents from the Massachusetts Fire Insurance Company, and rate quotes from the New York Life Insurance and Trust Company. 8 items. The Massachusetts Fire Insurance Company documents are housed in the Box 46 (oversize).
  - Portrait Collection, dates not examined; 2 folders (Folder 8-9)
    Collection of prints and photographs of many notable Americans represented in this collection. 2 folders, filed alphabetically. One oversize portrait of Abraham Lincoln is housed in Box 46 (oversize).
  - Stock Certificates, 1814-1858; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    Miscellaneous stock certificates certifying the purchase of shares in: privateer ship Orlando, the Kennebec Steam Navigation Company, the Boston Water Power Company, the Springfield Joint Stock Company, and the Boston Locomotive Works. 8 items.
  - Miscellaneous, 1768 August 22-1860 January 16; 1 folder
    Miscellaneous documents, filed by name.
    - Adams, George, 1800 November 6; 1 item (Folder 11)
      DS. Voucher and signed reimbursement for postage paid on letters of public service. 1 p.
    - Chase, Samuel, 1768 August 22; 1 item (Folder 11)
      DS. Petitioning the Rhode Island Assembly for a new trial, alleging mistreatment by court auditors. 1 p.
    - Christopher, H, 1860 January 16; 1 item (Folder 11)
      Professor of Chemistry and Natural History at Bethany College, [West] Virginia. ALS to A[ugustus] A[ddison] Gould. Informing Gould that his book on zoology is used as a textbook at Bethany College; asking whether he might write an accompanying volume on human physiology. 2 pp.
    - Livingston, R. M, 1813 June 9; 1 item (Folder 11)
      DS, Troy. A public denunciation of Samuel Starr. On the back is a very faded illustration of H. Van Schaick's land. 1 p.
    - Ringsley, W. W, 1849 February 25; 1 item (Folder 11)
      ALS, New London CT. To J. A. Rockwell. Requesting a copy of the President's message and congressional reports from 1848, as well as a account of the Navy's contracts for oakum. With negative comments on the nomination of a Mr. Cleveland. 1 p.
- Provenance, undated; 2 boxes
  These boxes contain materials saved by Andre De Coppet regarding the provenance and purchase of items in this collection. Most of the material consists of clippings from auction catalogues and letters from dealers. The material is organized alphabetically by name of subject; for example, provenance information for George Washington letters is filed under "Washington, George."
- 32101037474580 (Box 3)
- 32101037474564 (Box 1)
- 32101037474895 (Box 46)
- 32101037474572 (Box 2)
- 32101037474820 (Box 39)
- 32101037474598 (Box 4)
- 32101037474606 (Box 5)
- 32101037474911 (Box 5a)
- 32101037474614 (Box 6)
- 32101037474622 (Box 7)
- 32101037474630 (Box 8)
- 32101037474648 (Box 9)
- 32101037474655 (Box 10)
- 32101037474887 (Box 45)
- 32101037474663 (Box 11)
- 32101037474671 (Box 12)
- 32101037479948 (Box 13)
- 32101037479955 (Box 14)
- 32101037479963 (Box 15)
- 32101037479971 (Box 16)
- 32101037479989 (Box 17)
- 32101037479997 (Box 18)
- 32101037474465 (Box 19)
- 32101037474903 (Box 47)
- 32101037474473 (Box 20)
- 32101037474507 (Box 23)
- 32101037474481 (Box 21)
- 32101037474499 (Box 22)
- 32101037474515 (Box 24)
- 32101037474523 (Box 25)
- 32101037474531 (Box 26)
- 32101037474549 (Box 27)
- 32101037474556 (Box 28)
- 32101037474721 (Box 29)
- 32101037474739 (Box 30)
- 32101037474747 (Box 31)
- 32101037474754 (Box 32)
- 32101037474762 (Box 33)
- 32101037474770 (Box 34)
- 32101037474788 (Box 35)
- 32101037474796 (Box 36)
- 32101037474804 (Box 37)
- 32101037474812 (Box 38)
- 32101037474838 (Box 40)
- 32101037474846 (Box 41)
- 32101037474853 (Box 42)
- 32101037474861 (Box 43)
- 32101037474879 (Box 44)